<resources>
    <string name="app_name">4SightMyopiaExamination</string>
    <string name="title_activity_settings">Settings</string>
    <string name="title_activity_glasses">Glasses</string>
    <string name="worst">
        Your vision is estimated to be worse than 20/200. This is very serious. How are you able to read this?
    </string>
    <string name="info20200">
Your vision is estimated at 20/200 in this eye. The smallest letters read by somebody with 20/200 vision at 20 feet could be read at 200 feet by a person with normal (20/20) visual acuity.
Generally, in the US, individuals are required to wear corrective lenses if their vision is worse than 20/40 when driving to prevent automobile accidents. If you drive a vehicle, you should look into some form of visual aid.
Someone with 20/200 vision will be 10 times slower to spot a potential hazard in the distance compared to a person with 20/20 vision.
    </string>
    <string name="info20100">
        Your vision is estimated at 20/100 in this eye. The smallest letters read by somebody with 20/100 vision at 20 feet could be read at 100 feet by a person with normal (20/20) visual acuity.
Generally, in the US, individuals are required to wear corrective lenses if their vision is worse than 20/40 when driving to prevent automobile accidents. If you drive a vehicle, you should look into some form of visual aid.
Someone with 20/100 vision will be 5 times slower to spot a potential hazard in the distance compared to a person with 20/20 vision.


    </string>
    <string name="info2070">
Your vision is estimated at 20/70 in this eye. The smallest letters read by somebody with 20/70 vision at 20 feet could be read at 70 feet by
a person with normal (20/20) visual acuity.
Generally, in the US, individuals are required to wear corrective lenses if their vision is worse than 20/40 when driving to prevent automobile accidents. If you drive a vehicle, you should look into some form of visual aid.
Someone with 20/70 vision will be 3.5 times slower to spot a potential hazard in the distance compared to a person with 20/20 vision.

    </string>
    <string name="info2050">
Your vision is estimated at 20/50 in this eye. The smallest letters read by somebody with 20/50 vision at 20 feet could be read at 50 feet by a person with normal (20/20) visual acuity.
Generally, in the US, individuals are required to wear corrective lenses if their vision is worse than 20/40 when driving to prevent automobile accidents. If you drive a vehicle, you should look into some form of visual aid.
Someone with 20/50 vision will be 2.5 times slower to spot a potential hazard in the distance compared to a person with 20/20 vision.

    </string>
    <string name="info2040">
Your vision is estimated at 20/40 in this eye. The smallest letters read by somebody with 20/40 vision at 20 feet could be read at 40 feet by a person with normal (20/20) visual acuity.
    </string>
    <string name="info2030">
Your vision is estimated at 20/30 in this eye. The smallest letters read by somebody with 20/30 vision at 20 feet could be read at 30 feet by a person with normal (20/20) visual acuity.
    </string>
    <string name="info2025">
Your vision is estimated at 20/25 in this eye. The smallest letters read by somebody with 20/25 vision at 20 feet could be read at 25 feet by a person with normal (20/20) visual acuity.
    </string>
    <string name="info2020">
Your vision is estimated at 20/20 or better in this eye.You see perfectly!
    </string>
    <string name="glasses_text">
       "Cost: The average cost for standard prescription glasses is around $196 in the US. However,"
        "this price can fluctuate considerably depending on the features you choose, as well as the"
        "quality of the glasses, and whether or not you have insurance. High-end glasses can run for up"
        "to $1000. On the other extreme, $10 can buy a very basic pair. If you want a decent pair that"
        "can last a while and you don’t have insurance be prepared to pay at least $100.\n\n"

    "Keep in mind that a formal eye exam is also required. Without insurance, the average cost of an"
        "eye exam is around $200. Retailers such as Costco offer a discounted rate of around $50 for an"
        "eyeglass exam, but this price is available only to members. In addition, it is good practice to "
        "periodically reexamine eyes. If your vision has changed, you may need to get new glasses. "
        "Most doctors recommend annual checkups. This is done to make sure your prescription is up to"
        "date, so keep that in mind, especially if your vision is prone to change. \n\n"

    "If you have insurance, the price usually drops considerably. Of course, every health insurance"
        "plan is unique, but generally speaking, eye exams as well as glasses should be covered with a"
        "minimal copay of around $25. Some policies may also give $100-$200 a year to spend on "
        "eyewear, which means your glasses could be completely covered if you choose a pair in that"
        "price range. Check your insurance policy to see what coverage you qualify for to help minimize"
        "your out of pocket expense. With smart planning, a patient’s out of pocket expenses for"
        "eyeglasses could become negligible. \n\n"

    "Procurement Process: A formal eye exam is required. You can see an optometrist for this. "
        "LensCrafters, Costco and PearleVision all offer walk-in appointments for an eye exam."
        "Once the eye exam is concluded, you will choose a frame. Make sure to choose a high quality"
        "frame that fits your face, and is comfortable. Frames which are too tight or too heavy may"
        "cause headaches when worn for extended periods. \n\n"

"Advantages: \n"
"No recurring costs. Glasses can last a lifetime, barring a change in prescription or accident.\n"
"Safest, least invasive option. No surgery required.\n"
        "No risk of eye infection.\n"

"Disadvantages:\n"
      "Poorly fitted, or low quality glasses may cause headaches.\n\n"

"Options: Lens can include UV filters, anti refractive treatments for driving, and flipdown sunglasses."

    </string>
    <string name="contact_text">
    "Types: There are several different types of contact lenses and it is important to know which"
        "kind of get based on your needs. \n"

"When it comes to material, there are soft lenses, silicone hydrogel lenses, gas permeable lenses,"
        "hybrid contact lenses and pmma lenses. 64% of contact lenses prescribed in the U.S. are silicone hydrogel"
        "lenses. This is most likely due to the porosity of the material, which allows oxygen to reach your eye, "
        "as well as the softness and comfort of the lenses. Gas permeable lenses are more rigid, "
        "while PMMA lenses do not transmit oxygen to the eye. \n\n"

"When it comes to wearing time, there are 3 major types: daily wear and extended wear. Daily wear contact"
        "lenses are meant to be used for a single day, put on in the morning and removed and disposed of at night."
        "Extended wear contact lenses can be worn for several days, usually around a week, without removal.\n\n"

"Cost: It depends on what kind you get. Daily wear contact lenses are usually sold in boxes with 30 pairs, "
        "retailing for around $30 a box. If you wear contact lenses everyday, you are looking at spending about"
        "$700 a year on contacts. \n\n"

"Procurement Process: Like eyeglasses, you will need to have an eye exam with an optometrist. There, "
        "they will determine your prescription, and give you the option of ordering contact lenses in your"
        "prescription. Make sure the expiration date is far away enough such that the lenses don’t expire "
        "before you use them.\n\n"

"Advantages:\n"
        "Contact lenses move with your eye, allow a natural field of view, have no frames to obstruct your vision and greatly reduce distortions.\n"
"Unlike glasses, they do not fog up or get splattered by mud or rain.\n"
"Contact lenses are excellent for sports and other physical activities.\n"
"Many people feel they look better in contact lenses.\n"
"Compared to eyeglasses, they may offer better, more natural sight\n"

"Disadvantages:\n"
"Compared with glasses, contact lenses require a longer initial examination and more follow-up visits to maintain eye health. Lens care also requires more time."
        "If you are going to wear your lenses successfully, you will have to clean and store them properly,"
        "adhere to lens-wearing schedules and make appointments for follow-up care."
        "If you are wearing disposable or planned replacement lenses, you will have to carefully follow "
        "the schedule for throwing away used lenses\n\n"
"Safety Information: Please be extremely diligent about cleaning and removing your lenses. "
        "There have been many cases of people developing eye infections, even going blind, from improper "
        "usage of contact lenses. One case involved a woman who left her daily use contact lenses in for"
        "several weeks, and ended up going blind from a parasitic infection. You should wash your hands "
        "before inserting, removing and adjusting contact lenses. If you are wearing extended or continuous "
        "wear lenses, make sure to purchase contact lens solution, as well as a contact lens container. "
        "Contact lens containers should be replaced every few months, due to build up of bacteria. "
        "Do not take any risks when it comes to your eyesight!\n\n"
</string>
    <string name="prk_text">
        "PRK - Photorefractive Keratectomy (invasive)\n"
"Who is this for?\n"
"Important: consult an optometrist before considering this option. This guide is for informative purposes only. This is not an exhaustive list of surgical options."
"Invasive options for eye correction are only recommended for individuals over age 18, because their eyes may change until that point. Typically, surgery is for individuals"
        "who do not want to deal with the hassle of corrective lenses and want a permanent solution to their nearsightedness."
"PRK is less popular compared to LASIK, but there are some possible advantages that PRK has over LASIK.\n\n"

"How does it work?\n"
"Unlike LASIK, where the epithelial layer is temporarily removed, PRK permanently removes a layer."
"PRK then manually reshapes the cornea with an ultraviolet light beam to allow the eye to focus incoming light, increasing sharpness of vision."
"A contact lens is placed on the cornea to protect the eye while it regenerates the lost epithelial layer. \n\n"

"Cost:\n"
"A PRK procedure may cost from around $1,800 to $4,000 total. surgery is typically more expensive than any non-invasive vision option, and PRK is generally not covered by insurance.\n\n"


"Procurement Process:\n"
"Extensive consultation with an optometrist is mandatory. The optometrist will put a potential patient through an eye exam to determine what the right treatment will be."
        "The procedure itself is brief, around 15 minutes.\n\n"


"Advantages:\n"
"Permanent vision change\n"
"High success rate \n"
"Disadvantages:\n"
"Possible long-term complications:\n"
"Eye infections\n"
"Vision loss/damage\n"
"Chronic pain\n"
"Dry eyes\n\n"
"Usage instructions:\n"
"A post-PRK care plan will be given to the patient post-surgery. The most important thing is to follow those instructions, but here is a general guideline."
"Generally, keeping the eye moist with prescribed eye drops is common.Avoid straining the eyes and do not shower until a day after the surgery."
"Unlike LASIK, the cornea has to regrow the removed area, so there will most likely be side effects 2-4 days after the surgery. Over-the-counter painkillers and"
        "rest is a common way to deal with the discomfort."
"Meeting up with the optometrist post-surgery to remove the bandage contact lens is the next step, and they will give you instructions depending on the condition of the eye.\n\n"

"PRK vs LASIK\n"
"PRK is generally more of a straightforward procedure because the epithelial layer is not placed back on to the eye, avoiding corneal flap complications. "
        "It is also generally more inexpensive compared to LASIK. However, there is a higher risk of infection compared to LASIK, and there is a prolonged"
        "healing process as the body must regenerate epithelial cells. This means that the eyes will be more sensitive as they heal. Again, conversation "
        "with the optometrist is necessary to determine which option is best for you.\n\n"
    </string>
    <string name="lasik_text">
        "LASIK - (invasive)\n"
"Who is this for?\n"
"Important: consult an optometrist before considering this option. This guide is for informative purposes only. This is not an exhaustive list of surgical options."
"Invasive options for eye correction are only recommended for individuals over age 18, because their eyes may change until that point. Typically, surgery is for individuals "
        "who do not want to deal with the hassle of corrective lenses and want a permanent solution to their nearsightedness."
"LASIK is only one of many options for corrective surgery. Again, it is highly recommended that an optometrist be contacted for further discussion on invasive options.\n\n"

"How does it work?\n"
"LASIK first separates a layer of the eye called the epithelial layer. LASIK then manually reshapes the cornea with an ultraviolet light beam to allow the eye to focus incoming light, "
        "increasing sharpness of vision. The epithelial layer is then replaced.\n"
"Cost:\n"
"LASIK can range from $1,000 to $3,000 per eye. This price is generally all-encompassing, not just the surgery itself.surgery is typically more expensive than any non-invasive vision option, and LASIK is generally not covered by insurance\n"

"Procurement Process:\n"
"Extensive consultation with an optometrist is mandatory. The optometrist will put a potential patient through an eye exam to determine what the right treatment will be."
        "The procedure itself is brief, around 15 minutes.\n\n"

"Advantages:\n"
"Permanent vision change\n"
"High success rate (96% satisfaction (Journal of Cataract and Refractive Surgery))\n"
"Disadvantages:\n"
"Possible long-term complications:\n"
"Eye infections\n"
"Vision loss/damage\n"
"Chronic pain\n"
"Dry eyes\n\n"


"Usage Instructions:\n"
"https://www.nvisioncenters.com/lasik/post-care/"
"A post-LASIK care plan will be given to the patient post-surgery. The most important thing is to follow those instructions, but here is a general guideline. "
        "Generally, keeping the eye most with prescribed  eye drops is common. Avoid straining the eyes and do not shower until a day after the surgery. "
 "Meeting up with the optometrist post-surgery for follow-up sessions will most likely be in order."
"Some discomfort may be felt post-surgery as the eye adjusts to the changes. It is important not to disturb the eyes by rubbing them to give the eyes time to heal.\n\n"
"PRK vs LASIK\n"
"PRK is generally more of a straightforward procedure because the epithelial layer is not placed back on to the eye, avoiding corneal flap complications. "
        "It is also generally more inexpensive compared to LASIK. However, there is a higher risk of infection compared to LASIK, and there is a prolonged"
        "healing process as the body must regenerate epithelial cells. This means that the eyes will be more sensitive as they heal. Again, conversation "
        "with the optometrist is necessary to determine which option is best for you.\n\n"

    </string>
    <string name="orthok_text">
        "Ortho-K:\n\n"
"Who is this for?\n"
"Ortho-K is for individuals of all ages who want to avoid the hassle of wearing vision correcting objects but do not want invasive procedures like LASIK. Generally, Ortho-K offers a"
        "short-solution for nearsightedness.\n\n"

"How does it work?\n"
"Ortho-K lenses are a gas-permeable lens that gently reshapes the cornea while the user is asleep. The cornea remains in the flattened state for a temporary period, allowing sharper vision.\n"
"Overall, there will be around 3 pairs of lenses, each with a greater degree of correction. Once the user is at their desired level of vision, they will stay with the final pair,"
        "using them every night for correction.\n\n"
"Cost:\n"
"The re-shaping process requires multiple trips to the optometrist and possibly more than one set of lens to reshape the cornea. Generally, cost may range from $1,000 to $2,000,"
        "but some difficult cases may cost as much as $4,000. Significantly, Ortho-K is not completely covered by most insurance companies, so much of the cost will come out of "
        "the user’s pocket.\n\n"

"Procurement Process:\n"
"Like most other eye options, a formal eye exam is required. Your optometrist may measure your conrea’s shape to decide what type of lens to use. As mentioned earlier, "
        "multiple trips will be required to assess change in the cornea and determine if a change of lenses are required.\n\n"

"Advantages:\n"
"Ortho-K’s main advantage is that it is a non-invasive vision option that does not require vision correcting lenses during the day.\n"
"Ortho-K’s effects are not permanent, and this means that the option is relatively low-risk.\n"
"Disadvantages:\n"
"Ortho-K’s effects are not permanent, and that means routine application of the contact lenses during the night are required for clearer vision the next day."
        "Some may find this frustrating and opt for a more permanent solution.\n"
"Ortho-K requires putting on a pair of  contact lenses at night, and this may be uncomfortable for some users, resulting in lower sleep quality."
        "Typically, however, the lenses become more comfortable after repeated use.\n"
"While relatively cheap compared to invasive methods, Ortho-K typically costs around $1,000 to $2,000, which is significantly more than glasses.\n\n"
"Usage Instructions:\n"
"Instruction depends on the optometrist, and it is highly recommended that the user follow their instructions. However, the lenses are typically applied every night before sleep."
        "The optometrist will determine what lenses the patient will use. The lenses are not to be used after the patient wakes up.\n\n"
"Safety Information:\n"
"https://www.allaboutvision.com/contacts/orthok.htm\n"
"The website above mentions some effects while the eyes are still adjusting to the process - “blurred vision and glare and halos around lights”. Glasses may be worn to mitigate "
        "these temporary effects, but it is always safer to consult your optometrist before taking any measures.\n"
 </string>
    <string name="action_settings">Settings</string>
    <string name="title_activity_contacts">Contacts</string>
    <string name="title_activity_surgery">Surgery</string>
    <string name="title_activity_orthok">Orthok</string>
    <string name="title_activity_lasik">Lasik</string>
    <string name="large_text">
        "Material is the metaphor.\n\n"

        "A material metaphor is the unifying theory of a rationalized space and a system of motion."
        "The material is grounded in tactile reality, inspired by the study of paper and ink, yet "
        "technologically advanced and open to imagination and magic.\n"
        "Surfaces and edges of the material provide visual cues that are grounded in reality. The "
        "use of familiar tactile attributes helps users quickly understand affordances. Yet the "
        "flexibility of the material creates new affordances that supercede those in the physical "
        "world, without breaking the rules of physics.\n"
        "The fundamentals of light, surface, and movement are key to conveying how objects move, "
        "interact, and exist in space and in relation to each other. Realistic lighting shows "
        "seams, divides space, and indicates moving parts.\n\n"

        "Bold, graphic, intentional.\n\n"

        "The foundational elements of print based design typography, grids, space, scale, color, "
        "and use of imagery guide visual treatments. These elements do far more than please the "
        "eye. They create hierarchy, meaning, and focus. Deliberate color choices, edge to edge "
        "imagery, large scale typography, and intentional white space create a bold and graphic "
        "interface that immerse the user in the experience.\n"
        "An emphasis on user actions makes core functionality immediately apparent and provides "
        "waypoints for the user.\n\n"

        "Motion provides meaning.\n\n"

        "Motion respects and reinforces the user as the prime mover. Primary user actions are "
        "inflection points that initiate motion, transforming the whole design.\n"
        "All action takes place in a single environment. Objects are presented to the user without "
        "breaking the continuity of experience even as they transform and reorganize.\n"
        "Motion is meaningful and appropriate, serving to focus attention and maintain continuity. "
        "Feedback is subtle yet clear. Transitions are efﬁcient yet coherent.\n\n"

        "3D world.\n\n"

        "The material environment is a 3D space, which means all objects have x, y, and z "
        "dimensions. The z-axis is perpendicularly aligned to the plane of the display, with the "
        "positive z-axis extending towards the viewer. Every sheet of material occupies a single "
        "position along the z-axis and has a standard 1dp thickness.\n"
        "On the web, the z-axis is used for layering and not for perspective. The 3D world is "
        "emulated by manipulating the y-axis.\n\n"

        "Light and shadow.\n\n"

        "Within the material environment, virtual lights illuminate the scene. Key lights create "
        "directional shadows, while ambient light creates soft shadows from all angles.\n"
        "Shadows in the material environment are cast by these two light sources. In Android "
        "development, shadows occur when light sources are blocked by sheets of material at "
        "various positions along the z-axis. On the web, shadows are depicted by manipulating the "
        "y-axis only. The following example shows the card with a height of 6dp.\n\n"

        "Resting elevation.\n\n"

        "All material objects, regardless of size, have a resting elevation, or default elevation "
        "that does not change. If an object changes elevation, it should return to its resting "
        "elevation as soon as possible.\n\n"

        "Component elevations.\n\n"

        "The resting elevation for a component type is consistent across apps (e.g., FAB elevation "
        "does not vary from 6dp in one app to 16dp in another app).\n"
        "Components may have different resting elevations across platforms, depending on the depth "
        "of the environment (e.g., TV has a greater depth than mobile or desktop).\n\n"

        "Responsive elevation and dynamic elevation offsets.\n\n"

        "Some component types have responsive elevation, meaning they change elevation in response "
        "to user input (e.g., normal, focused, and pressed) or system events. These elevation "
        "changes are consistently implemented using dynamic elevation offsets.\n"
        "Dynamic elevation offsets are the goal elevation that a component moves towards, relative "
        "to the component’s resting state. They ensure that elevation changes are consistent "
        "across actions and component types. For example, all components that lift on press have "
        "the same elevation change relative to their resting elevation.\n"
        "Once the input event is completed or cancelled, the component will return to its resting "
        "elevation.\n\n"

        "Avoiding elevation interference.\n\n"

        "Components with responsive elevations may encounter other components as they move between "
        "their resting elevations and dynamic elevation offsets. Because material cannot pass "
        "through other material, components avoid interfering with one another any number of ways, "
        "whether on a per component basis or using the entire app layout.\n"
        "On a component level, components can move or be removed before they cause interference. "
        "For example, a floating action button (FAB) can disappear or move off screen before a "
        "user picks up a card, or it can move if a snackbar appears.\n"
        "On the layout level, design your app layout to minimize opportunities for interference. "
        "For example, position the FAB to one side of stream of a cards so the FAB won’t interfere "
        "when a user tries to pick up one of cards.\n\n"
    </string>
    <string name="title_activity_prk">PRK</string>git

    <string name="proper_eyecare_text">
        "General eyecare:\n"

        "To keep you eye healthy here are a few easy steps to avoid damaging your eyes during your"
        "day to day life.\n"
        "1. Wear sunglasses. Most sunglasses reduced the amount of both UVA and UVB radiation that "
        "the retina receives in adults. However, while most sunglasses reduce a large amount of UVB "
        "radiation the amount of UVA reduces is highly dependent on the glasses.\n"

        "2. Wear eye protection. When playing doing work that involves sharp objects or even playing"
        " certain sports such as racquetball wearing proper eye protection can significantly reduce "
        "the chance of eye injury.\n"

        "3. Eat a balanced diet and stay active\n"

        "\n"
        "Myopia prevention\n"

        "The risk of myopia can be reduced by exposure to daylight and increased by performing close"
        "up work. \“A person with little exposure to daylight has a fivefold risk of developing "
        "myopia, which can rise as high as a 16-fold risk if that person also performs close-up "
        "work\". It is recommended that children be exposed to approximately 2 hours of daylight per"
        " day to prevent myopia. In addition, Progression of myopia can be reduced by administering "
        "atropine 0.01% eye drops as indicated and prescribed by the treating ophthalmologist."
        " Effects must be monitored approximately every 6 months. \n\n"



        " https://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/pmc/articles/PMC5615392/"
    </string>
    <string name="title_activity_log">Log</string>
    <string name="title_activity_save_to_log">SaveToLog</string>


    <string name="snellen_instructions_text">
        1) Find a quiet area to conduct your test.\n
        2) Place the phone at eye level approximately 5 meters away.\n
        3) To test your left eye cover your right eye. To test your right eye cover your left eye.
        to test both don\'t cover either eye.\n
        4) When a letter appears on the screen, read the letter loud enough that the phone can hear it\n
        5) The test will continue until you reach the smallest font size or you incorrectly read 3
        letters of the same font size.\n
    </string>

    <string name="tumbling_instructions_text">
        1) Find a quiet area to conduct your test.\n
        2) Place the phone at eye level approximately 5 meters away.\n
        3) To test your left eye cover your right eye. To test your right eye cover your left eye.
        to test both don\'t cover either eye.\n
        4) When an E appears on the screen, indicate the direction of the E loud enough that the
        phone can hear it. (E.g. "Up", "Down", "Left", "Right")\n
        5) The test will continue until you reach the smallest font size or you incorrectly read 3
        letters of the same font size.\n
    </string>

    <string name="instructions_text">
        1) Place the phone at eye level approximately 5 meters away.\n
        2) As the test proceeds it will prompt you to close your left or right eye. When prompted
        close that eye and than read aloud the letters that appears on the screen of your device.\n
        3) The test will continue until you reach the smallest font size or you incorrectly read 3
        letters of the same font size.
        size.\n
    </string>

    <string name="lorem_ipsum">
        Lorem ipsum dolor sit amet, consectetur adipiscing elit, sed do eiusmod tempor incididunt ut labore et dolore magna aliqua.
    </string>

    <string name="snellenButton">
        Snellen
    </string>
    <string name="floatingEButton">
        Floating E
    </string>
    <string name="testType">
        Select which test you would like to take
    </string>
    <string name="startTestWithInstructions">
        Instructions
    </string>
    <string name="startTestWithoutInstructions">
        Start Exam
    </string>

    <string name="title_activity_slider">SLIDER</string>
</resources>
